Register of the National Republic records, 1918-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
National Republic records
1918-1960
60006
Hoover Institution Archives
735 microfilm reels, 76 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 168 card file boxes, 4 sound discs (143.0 linear feet)
Clippings, printed matter, pamphlets, reports, indices, notes, bulletins, lettergrams, weekly letters, and photographs relating to pacifist, communist, fascist, and other radical movements, and to political developments in the United States and the Soviet Union.
National Republic
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1960.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The National Republic (subtitle, "magazine of fundamental Americanism") was published by the National Republic Publishing Co. in Washington, D.C. It was established in March 1905 and ceased publication with v. 47, no. 11 in March 1960. Until March 1925, it was published under the title National Republican. The magazine, an illustrated monthly, focused on political affairs in the United States, particularly with regard to internal security and communist activities. By the time it ceased publication in 1960, it had achieved a circulation of about 20,000.
Scope and Content of Collection
Clippings, printed matter, pamphlets, reports, indices, notes, bulletins, lettergrams, weekly letters, and photographs relating to pacifist, communist, fascist, and other radical movements, and to political developments in the United States and the Soviet Union.
Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism--Soviet Union.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Fascism.; Pacifism.; Peace.; Phonorecords.; Radicalism--United States.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Soviet Union.; Subversive activities--United States.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government.
- MICROFILMED MATERIAL
- Information File A (Boxes 1-398)
  Scope and Contents note
  Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, printed matter, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject. For additional data on organizations, individuals, and subjects identified in this series, see also the general letter folders in Information Files B and C.
  - A, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Actors Equity
  - Academy of Political Science
  - Adamic, Louis
  - Advertising
  - Agriculture
  - Aid to Britain
  - Air Corps and Aviation
  - Allen, Devere
  - Al, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Amerasia
  - Ameriaki Magyar
  - America First Committee
  - America First, Inc.
  - American for God Crusade
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science
  - American Action Inc.
  - American Action Inc. (Box 3)
  - American Alliance
  - American Artists Congress
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - American Association for Economic Freedom
  - American Association for China Famine and Flood Relief
  - American Association for Labor Legislation
  - American Association for Old Age Security
  - American Association for U.N.
  - American Association of University Women
  - American Association of University Professors
  - American Bar Association
  - American Bible Society
  - American China Policy Association (Box 4)
  - American Christian Palestine Committee
  - American Citizens Protective Association
  - American Citizenship Foundation
  - American Coalition [2 folders]
  - American Boycott Against Aggressor Nations
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees
  - American Committee for Democratic and Intellectual Freedom
  - American Committee for Defense of British Homes
  - American Committee for Italian Democracy
  - American Committee for Non-participation in Japanese Aggression
  - American Committee for Outlawry of War
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born [2 folders] (Box 5)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom
  - American Committee for Yugoslav Relief
  - American Committee to Save Refugees
  - American Commonwealth Federation
  - American Council for Democratic Greece
  - American Council on Education
  - American Council on Public Affairs (Box 6)
  - American Council on Soviet Relations
  - American Defenders
  - American Defenders of Freedom
  - American Defense Society
  - American Destiny Party
  - American Direct Action, Inc.
  - American Discussion League, Inc.
  - American Economic Association
  - American Economists' Council for the Study of Branch Banking
  - American Educational League
  - American Educational Association
  - American Ethical Union (see Encampment for Citizenship)
  - American Financiers Investigation and Protective League
  - American First Commitees
  - American Forward Movement
  - American Friends of Aid to Russia
  - American Friends of Albania
  - American Friends of Chinese People
  - American Friends of Danish Freedom and Democracy
  - American Friends of German Freedom
  - American Friends of Greece
  - American Friends of Polish Democracy
  - American Friends Service Committee
  - Aliens (Box 7)
    - General
      - General
      - 1930-1934
      - 1935
      - 1936-1937
      - 1938
      - 1939
      - 1940-1946
    - Communists
      - General
      - Lulinsky case
    - Jouhaux, Leon
    - Mann, Thomas
    - Strachey, John
    - Strecker, Joseph
    - Toller, Ernst
    - Criminal (Box 8)
    - German refugees - relief
    - Refugees relief
    - Alien Russian
    - Aliens - enemy
    - Addresses, Congressional (Box 9)
    - Articles
    - Government booklets [not in a folder]
    - Legislation
      - Clippings
      - Releases [2 folders]
    - Legislation (Box 10)
    - Legislation (Box 11)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 12)
    - [3 folders], 1946-1951
    - Reports on
    - Pamphlets (Box 13)
    - Branches
    - 1923-1929
    - 1930-1932
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935-1936 (Box 14)
    - 1937-1938
    - 1939
    - Chicago Civil Liberties Committee
    - Releases
    - Letterheads
  - American Fund for Public Service (Box 15)
  - American Gospel Crusaders
  - American Guard
  - American Guild for German Cultural Freedom Inc.
  - American Historical Association
  - American Independence League
  - American Institute of Public Opinion
  - American Interracial Seminar
  - American Investors' Union
  - American Irish Defense Association
  - American Legion (See Veterans)
  - American League for a Free Palestine Inc.
  - American Labor Party [3 folders]
  - American Labor Party [4 folders] (Box 16)
  - American League for Good Government
  - American League for Human Rights
  - American League for India's Freedom
  - American League to Abolish Capital Punishment
  - American Library League
  - American Management Association
  - American Medical Relief for Italy (Box 17)
  - American Mercury
  - American National Vigilantes Intelligence League
  - American Nationalist Committee
  - American Nationalist Party
  - American Observer
  - American Overseas Aid and U.N. Appeal for Children
  - American Palestine Committee (See also American Christian Palestine Committee)
  - American Party - Young Americans
  - American Patriots Against Foreign Wars Inc.
  - American People's Fund Inc.
  - American Polish Labor Council
  - American Political Science Association
  - American Prophetic League Inc.
  - American Protective League
  - American Protestant Defense League
  - American Publishing Society
  - American Relief for Germany
  - American Relief of Greek Democracy
  - American Russian Chamber of Commerce
  - American Russian Institute [2 folders]
  - American School of Christian Democracy [2 folders]
  - American Slav Congress
  - American Society for China Inc. (Box 18)
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia
  - American Society for Russian Relief
  - American Technotax Society
  - American Telegraph and Telephone
  - American Trade Council
  - American Tribunal
  - American Union for Democracy
  - American Unity League Inc.
  - American Youth Congress (See Youth...)
  - American War Dads
  - American Workers Party
  - Americanism
  - Americanism Educational League
  - Americans Inc.
  - Amlie, Thomas B.
  - Americans for Democratic Action
    - Clippings
    - Literature [3 folders] (Box 19)
  - Amtorg (Box 20)
  - Am
    - Miscellaneous
      - General
      - A-B
      - C-E
      - F-H
      - I-K
      - Q-S
      - T-Z (Box 21)
    - Clippings
    - Pamphlets
  - American League Against War and Fascism
    - General
    - 1933
    - 1934
    - 1935
    - 1936 (Box 22)
      - General
      - Third Congress Against War and Facism
    - 1937
    - General [2 folders]
    - General (Box 23)
  - American League for Peace and Democracy
    - General
    - Dies Committee expose
    - General (Box 24)
      - [2 folders], 1938
      - [2 folders], 1939
      - 1940
  - American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) (Box 25)
    - CIO Against Free Enterprise
    - CIO. Political Action Committee
      - General
      - Pamphlets (Box 26)
    - AFL
      - General
        - 1923-1935
        - 1937
      - Committee for Unemployment Insurance and Relief and National Congress for Unemployment and Social Insurance
      - General (Box 27)
        - General [2 folders]
        - 1938
    - AFL pamphlets (Box 28)
    - CIO literature
    - CIO Union publications (Box 29)
    - AFL-CIO affiliates
    - AFL-CIO affiliates, clippings
      - General (Box 30)
        - 1937
        - [2 folders], 1938
        - 1939
        - 1940-1943
        - Clippings, 1937 (Box 31)
      - Dies Committee expose
    - CIO strikes
      - Maritime unions
      - United Steel Workers (Steel Workers Organizing Committee)
      - United Auto Workers
      - United Mine Workers
      - Clippings
    - AFL-CIO strikes
      - General
      - Leninism-Lewisism (Box 32)
    - CIO affiliates
      - Distributive, Processing and Office Workers [2 folders]
      - American Communications Association [2 folders]
      - American Radio Telegraphists Association and American Communication Association
      - American Communications Association [2 folders]
      - American Radio Telegraphists Association
      - American Newspaper Guild (Box 33)
      - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
      - Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists and Technicians
      - Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Workers
      - Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America
      - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union
      - International Fur and Leather Workers Union
      - International Furniture Makers of America
      - International Union of Electric, Radio, and Machine Workers [2 folders]
      - International Union of Electric, Radio and Machine Workers, pamphlets [2 folders] (Box 34)
      - International Woodworkers of America
      - National Maritime Union
      - State County and Municipal Workers of America (Box 35)
      - Transport Workers Union of America
      - Steel Workers Organizing Committee
      - United Auto Workers of America
      - United Federal Workers of America
      - United Mine Workers
      - Office and Professional Workers of America
      - United Packinghouse Workers of America (Box 36)
      - United Public Workers of America
      - United Shoe Workers of America and United Shoe and Leather Union
      - Utility Workers Union of America and Utility Workers Union of America Organizing Committee
      - United Steel Workers of America
      - Textile Workers Organizing Committee and United Textile Workers Union
    - AFL-CIO articles [2]
    - Literature (Box 37)
    - CIO personnel (Box 38)
      - General
      - Communists
      - Women
      - Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union
      - Leaders
      - American Newspaper Guild
      - National Maritime Union
      - Textile Workers Union
      - Transport Workers Union
      - United Auto Workers Union
      - United Electric, Radio and Machine Workers (Box 39)
      - United Mine Workers Union
      - Harry Bridges [2 folders]
      - Harry Bridges [3 folders] (Box 40)
      - Harry Bridges, Dies Committee expose
      - John A. Brophy
      - Joseph Curran
      - Richard Frankensteen
      - Francis J. Gorman
      - John L. Lewis
      - Homer Martin (Box 41)
      - Philip Murray
      - Michael J. Quill
      - John Santo
      - Mark Starr
    - Stolberg articles
    - Pamphlets
  - Anarchism
  - Anastasia (Box 42)
  - Anderson, Jane
  - Anderson, Mary
  - Anglo-Saxon Federation of Americans
  - Anti-War and Fascist Movement
  - American League Against Communism
  - American Women Against Communism
  - Methodist League Against Communism, Fascism and Unpatriotic Pacifism
  - American Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature
  - Antarctic
  - Anti-Communist Legislation
  - Anti-Communist Organization and Activities (Box 43)
  - Anti-Imperialist League
  - Joint Anti-Facist Refugee Committee
  - Anti-Nazi Movement
  - Arabs
  - Arden House (American Assembly)
  - Arbitrator (Box 44)
  - Argentina
  - Arkansas
  - Armenia
  - Army
  - Army (U.S.) Exercise "Long Horn" (Box 45)
  - "Appreciate America"
  - Armaments
  - Armaments, Navy
  - Armaments, Navy, literature
  - Arms Embargo
  - Art - 2 (Box 46)
  - Art - Artists
  - Ashcraft, M. B. (Mrs.)
  - Astor, Lady
  - American Association for the Advancement of Atheism
  - Atheism [2 folders]
  - Atheists
  - Atheist Organizations (Box 47)
  - Atlantic Pact
  - Atomic bomb [2 folders]
  - Atomic bomb, clippings
  - Atomic bomb, literature (Box 48)
  - Austria (Box 49)
  - Australia
  - A, miscellaneous
  - B, miscellaneous
  - Baker, Newton D.
  - Baldwin, Roger
  - Banking [2 folders] (Box 50)
  - Banking, radical influence
  - Banking, clippings
  - Barlow, Lester P.
  - Baruch, Bernard
  - Bar, miscellaneous (Box 51)
  - Bas, miscellaneous
  - Bennett, Helen Christine
  - Berry, George L.
  - Better America Federation
  - Be, miscellaneous
  - Birth control
  - Birth control, literature
  - Birth control, clippings
  - Bi, miscellaneous (Box 52)
  - Bl, miscellaneous
  - Black Legion
  - Black, Robert I.
  - Bolivia
  - Bomberger, Dr. Henry A.
  - Bombings
  - Bonus marches
  - Bonus march, 1933
  - Bonus march, 1932
  - Bookings Corporation
  - Borah, William E.
  - Boycott (Box 53)
  - Boyscouts
  - Bo, miscellaneous
  - Brazil
  - Brandeis, Louis D.
  - Br, miscellaneous
  - Bu, miscellaneous
  - Buchman, Frank (See Oxford Group Movement)
  - Browne, Herbert J. (Bulletin) (Box 54)
  - Bro, miscellaneous
  - Budenz, Louis F.
  - Budget Plan
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie
  - Bulgaria
  - Bureau of University Travel
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray [2 folders]
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Box 55)
  - Butler, Maj. Gen. Smedley D.
  - "Buy American"
  - Bu, miscellaneous
  - Buchman, Frank (See Oxford Group Movement)
  - Cain, Harry P. (Box 56)
  - Canada
  - Campbell, Thomas D.
  - Capitalism
  - C, miscellaneous
  - Carlson, John Roy
    - General
    - General (Box 57)
    - Comic strip
    - Clippings
    - Photostats
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman
  - Car, miscellaneous
  - Censorship (Box 58)
  - Centralization of government
  - Ce, miscellaneous
  - Chain stores
  - Chamberlin, William H.
  - Chamber of Commerce
  - Chandler, Albert B. ("Happy")
  - Chaplin, Charles
  - Chappell, Winifred
  - Chapple, John B.
  - Charts, #1
  - Charts, #2 (Box 59)
  - Chase National Bank
  - Chase, Stuart
  - Child labor
  - Child Labor Amendment
  - Child labor, National Child Labor Committee
  - Child Study Association of America
  - Child Study Association of America, pamphlets
  - Child welfare (Box 60)
  - Child welfare, pamphlets
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection
  - Chile
  - China (Box 61)
  - China Aid Movements
  - China Institute of America
  - Chinese Exclusion Laws
  - Chinese-Japanese relations (Box 62)
    - General
    - 1931
  - Christian Advocate
  - Christian American Association
  - Christian American Crusade
  - Christian Century
  - Christian Front
  - Christian Herald
  - Christians, George W.
  - Churchill, Winston
  - Ch, miscellaneous (Box 63)
  - Churches
    - General
    - Baptist (Box 64)
    - Catholic
      - General
      - Pamphlets
    - Congregational Christian
    - Lutheran (Box 65)
    - Board of Christian Education of the Evangelical and Reformed Church
    - Methodist
      - Radicalism
      - General (Box 66)
    - Presbytarian
    - Radicalism
    - Organizations (Box 67)
      - General
      - Church League for Industrial Democracy
        - General
        - Literature
      - Methodist Federation for Social Service (Action) (Box 68)
  - Cincinnatus
  - Citizens Committee for National War Services Act
  - Citizens Committee for U.N. Reform, Inc.
  - Citizens Council for the U.S.
  - Citizens United to Abolish the Wood-Rankin Committee
  - Citizens (Congressional Hearings) (Box 69)
  - Citizens for Victory
  - Citizens Military Training Camps [2 folders]
  - Citizens National Committee (Citizens Emergency Committee of Non-Defense Expenditures) [2 folders]
  - Citizens Non-Partisan Committee for the Serviceman's Vote
  - Citizenship (Box 70)
  - Citizens Union
  - Citizens U.S.A. Committee
  - Civic Education Service
  - Civil Rights Federation
  - Civil Rights Congress
  - Civil Service
  - Civil Works Administration (Box 71)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps
  - Clearing House for National Interests
  - Close, Upton
  - Clergy
    - General
    - Cadman, S. Parkes
    - Coughlin, Rev. Charles E.
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson
    - Holmes, John Haynes
    - Jones, Rev. E. Stanley
    - McConnell, Francis J. (Bishop)
    - Manning, William (Bishop)
    - Muste, Dr. A. J.
    - Niebuhr, Dr. Reinhold
    - Orlemanski, Father Stanslaus
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley (Box 72)
    - Ryan, John A. (Msgr)
    - Spofford, William
    - Ward, Rev. Harry F. (American League Against War and Fascism)
    - Walsh, Father Edmund A.
    - Williams, Howard Y.
    - Winrod, Rev. Gerald
  - Ch, miscellaneous (Box 73)
    - Clippings
    - Pamphlets
  - Communism
    - General
      - 1918-1931
      - 1932-1934
      - 1935-1936
      - 1937
      - 1938 (Box 74)
      - 1939
    - Data compiled by Walter Steele
    - Pamphlets
    - Pamphlets (Box 75)
    - Excerpts from Soviet documents
  - Communist activities
    - Communism Against Industry, Life Insurance, and Religion
    - Communist Attacks on Patriots
    - General (Box 76)
      - 1922-1930
      - 1932
      - 1934
      - 1935-1936
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939
      - 1940
      - 1931 (Box 77)
      - 1933
    - Armed forces [3 folders]
    - Colorado
    - Labor unions [2 folders] (Box 78)
    - Farmers (Box 79)
    - Labor unions (office worker unions)
    - Trade Union Unity League
    - Negro [2 folders]
    - Merchant Marine, shipping (Box 80)
    - Force and violence
    - South (USA)
    - Washington, D.C. (handbills, circulars, leaflets, etc.)
    - Veterans (Box 81)
    - Theater
    - New York Welfare Department
    - Strikes
    - West Coast [2 folders] (Box 82)
    - Communist Activities in foreign countries (Box 83)
    - South, Central and Latin America
    - Australia
    - Austria
    - Baltic states
    - Belgium
    - Brazil
    - Bulgaria
    - Canada
    - Chile (Box 84)
    - China
      - Clippings [3 folders]
      - General
    - Cuba
    - Czechoslavakia (Box 85)
    - England
    - Finland
    - France
    - Germany (Box 86)
    - Greece
    - Guatemala
    - Holland
    - Hawaii
    - Hungary
    - India
    - Iran
    - Ireland
    - Italy
    - Japan (Box 87)
    - Mexico
    - Norway, Sweden and Denmark
    - Philippines
    - Poland
    - Portugal
    - Romania
    - Turkey
    - Yugoslavia
    - Spain
  - Communist party (Box 88)
    - 1925-1929
    - 1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934
    - 1935
    - 1936 (Box 89)
    - 1937
    - 1938
    - 1939
    - 1940 (Box 90)
    - 1941
    - 1942
    - 1943
    - 1944
    - 1945
    - 1946
    - 1947
  - Communist Political Association
  - Communists (Box 91)
    - General
      - General [2 folders]
      - A-D
      - E-H
      - I-L
      - M-P
      - Q-U
      - V-Z
    - Europe
    - Daily Worker
    - Police correspondence
    - Amter, Israel
    - Beal, Fred E.
    - Benjamin, Herbert
    - Blumberg, Albert
    - Browder, Earl [3 folders] (Box 92)
    - Leaders
    - Iron Curtain prisoners (Box 93)
    - Photographs and records
    - Photograph album
    - Darcy, Sam
    - Davis, Benjamin J., Jr.
    - Dozenberg, Nicholas
    - Foster, William Z.
    - Levovich, (Sol) Erenberg
    - Eisler, Gerhard and Hanns
    - Ford, James W.
    - Gallacher, Leo
    - Gannes, Harry
    - Gerson, Simon
    - Gitlow, Benjamin
    - Gold, Michael (Box 94)
    - National Republic's Rogues Gallery
    - Radicals
    - American Citizens
    - Candidates
    - Communists, miscellaneous [2 folders]
    - Lists
    - Clippings
    - Washington, D.C. (Box 95)
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Supporters
    - Hathaway, Clarence
    - Heller, A. A.
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - Mann, Tom
    - Minor, Robert
    - Schneiderman, William
    - Stachel, Jack
    - Steffens, Lincoln
    - Sugar, Maurice
    - Sullivan, Jerry
    - Weiner, William
    - Michigan
    - Illinois
    - California
    - New York
    - Maryland and Washington, D.C.
    - Ohio
    - Wisconsin (Milwaukee)
  - Communist women (Box 96)
    - General
    - Berkman, Edith
    - Burlak, Ann
    - Goldman, Emma
    - Winter, Ella
    - Bloor, Ella Reeve
  - Clay Naff articles
  - Communist International [2 folders]
  - Communist International (Box 97)
  - Communist - court cases
    - General
    - 12 Board members
    - Briefs (Box 98)
  - Communists, Hunger March [2 folders], 1931-1932
  - Communist colonies, U.S.A.
  - Communist book shops and publishing work (Box 99)
    - General
    - Abraham Lincoln Book Shop
    - Workers Library Publishers
    - Handbills
    - Catalogues
    - Periodicals (Box 100)
    - Washington Co-operative Bookshop, Bookshop Association, Modern Bookshop, International Bookshop
    - Publications [2 folders]
    - Daily Worker clippings (Box 101)
    - Daily Worker, miscellaneous
    - Literature, children
    - Subscription offers
    - Midwest Daily Record
    - Foreign language publications
    - Jewish publications
    - Jewish publications (Box 102)
    - Revolutionary Age
    - Songs
    - Photostats
  - Communist cultural activities
    - Red Channels, published by Alert
    - Camps (Box 103)
    - Publications
    - General
    - Movements
      - General
      - People's Radio Foundation
    - People's Songs Inc. [2 folders] (Box 104)
    - Stage for Action
    - Record clubs
    - Theatre, radio, television
    - Art
    - Robinson, Earl ("Ballad for America")
    - Publications
    - Workers clubs
    - Women
    - Lists
    - Subsidiary movements
    - Finances [2 folders] (Box 105)
    - Communist League of America (Trotsky movements, 4th International)
    - Communist United Front
    - Communist organization report, by Walter A. Johnson
    - Communist Party petition signers [2 folders]
    - State movements (Box 106)
      - Michigan
      - Minnesota
      - Ohio